No matter what, you stick with your
race. I don't know why I can't have a
Mexican friend. He's in my cell. I don't
know what the is going on, but
Mexican got on boots and I got to figure
out what I'm supposed to do now.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Thank you everybody.
Uh on this show, here's what happens.
Just a bunch of comics telling true
stories and that's all it is. Please
give it up for Amy Sadique. Everybody
let him hear.
My story is about prison danger. seeing
that I look so menacing,
you know, and I'm black, so you know
it's going to be about crime.
Let me tell you, prison is a is a odd
place because you do not know the rules.
No matter how many prison movies you
watched and documentaries of locked up,
you still don't know the rules of what's
going to happen. So, I'm on my way
to what they call necessities.
Necessities is, you know, where your
clothes, you get your laundry and all
that So, I'm walking to
Necessities and a dude just walks by and
say, "Mexican got on boots." I like,
"What the does that mean?"
Cuz it's like I'm I've been in prison
like the first day. What you mean
Mexican got on boots? Everybody got on
boots. So I thought dude walk
past, Mexican got on boots. Mexican got
on boots. So I tell somebody else,
Mexican got on boots.
Dude look down and say Mexican do have
on boots and just take off running.
I'm like,
was I supposed to run?
Cuz the Mexicans have on boots.
So I asked the old dude. I said, "Hey,
Mexican got on boots." He say, "All
right, they got on boots." I said, "What
that mean?" He say, "It's going to be a
riot."
I said, "You pretty calm about a riot."
I said, "How you know Mexicans got on
boots mean it's going to have a riot?"
He said, "Cuz Mexicans don't wear boots
on the wrecky yard." I said, "Okay, what
they wear in the wrecky yard?" He say,
"Sneakers. They play handball all the
time. And then you looking, you see
Mexicans over there playing handball,
but they got on boots.
So I'm like,
doesn't still don't comprehend. So I get
back to myself. I say, "Hey, to my
you Mexican. What Mexican got on boots
mean?" He say, "That mean we going to
ride. We going to stab a couple of black
guys up.
[Laughter]
And I asked this this when you in
prison, you ask dumb ass question. I'm
like, does the ride happen in here?
Like in this cell?
Cuz me and you just finished eating
together. What you mad at me about? I
don't know. But this when you learn that
you stick with your race in prison, no
matter what, you stick with your race. I
don't know why I can't have a Mexican
friend. He's in my cell. I don't know
what the is going on, but Mexican
got on boots and I got to figure out
what I'm supposed to do now.
And I still don't know. I got to still
ask people.
Found a black dude. I'm like, yo. So
what I do now? The Mexican got on boots.
He say, you got to find you a knife. I
said, "I got to find a knife. Ain't no
You can't have no knife in prison." He
said, "You just got here, huh?" I said,
"Yeah, I just got here." He said, "Man,
look, you going to need to find a dude
named Cece and get you a knife.
There's 3,000 people on this unit. How
the I'm supposed to find Cece? I
don't know."
So, I'm just walking around. Miss Got on
Boots. CeCe.
Mexican on boots CC.
Dude say, "Hey, you looking for Cece?" I
said, "Yeah, you must need a knife." I
said, "Yeah." He said, "Why you need a
knife?" I said, "You ain't heard?" He
said, "No, I ain't heard I've been
a work all day." Mexican got on boots.
He take off running.
[Applause]
I take off running after him only
because he never told me what CeCe was.
I catch him. He say, "Man, go in the
wrecky yard. CeCe going to be on the
wrecky yard." And I'm like, "I don't
want to go in the wrecky yard. I just
left the wrecky yard." That's how I
found out Mexican had on boots.
So, I'm sitting on the wrecky yard
looking around for somebody who may look
like a dude named CeCe.
So, I'm asking, I'm looking. I'm
waiting. I say somebody going to speak
to Cece. Got to dude walk. What up,
CeCe? I said, "That's who I'm looking
for right there." I see CeCe. I nod. He
nod back. I say, "Can I come over
there?" He said, "Come on, young blood."
I get over there. I say, "Hey, CeCe
Mexican got on boots." He said, "I
heard." I say, "I need a knife." He
said, "Well, come to my sale in a couple
of minutes. I'mma hook you up." I get to
the sale. I say, "Cece, I need a knife."
He said, "Which the turned
different." He said, "What type of
knife?" I don't know. I just got
here.
He said, "What type of knife you looking
for?" I say, "Something sharp, something
to poke a with." I don't
know. So he put up a towel and say,
"Hold on, let me show you some knives."
He put up a towel, went under this
mattress, took some out, slid some
back, and now it's eight knives in
front of me. It's like I'm at
Macy's. I'm like, "Yo."
I'm like, you know, he what kind of
knife you want? I said, "Well, you know
what kind of knife I need for a ride? I
ain't never been to ride before." He
said, "Well, you going to need something
where you can stick multiple people and
it break off."
I said, "Is that right here on the
thing?" He said, "No, these are personal
knives. What kind of what you want your
knife made out of?" I said, "This too
many choices, man. I just need a
knife to protect myself." He said,
"Well, god damn it. Listen to me, man.
Do you want it made out of wood,
plastic, metal, or what?" I say, "Cece,
listen to me. I don't know cuz I never
been to ride before. What's going to
protect me?" He say, "Fuck new ass
motherfucker."
Like, it's wrong to be just getting to
prison. I don't want to be here from the
beginning.
So, calling me new don't mean to
me.
So I said, "So man, what would you
suggest?" He said, "I suggest something
personal, like a pen top." Pen top? No
pen top knife. I want a real
knife. Something I can just get in there
with. He say, "No, what you get a pen
top is a knife with a pen, but you push
a nail through it and then you put the
top on it and just have it in your
pocket so we can walk around with it." I
said, "That sound pretty cool, but can
they would that sustain with a riot?" He
say, "No, this ain't that ain't riot
knives. That's just personal walk
around." I said, "Motherfucker, I need a
knife for the riot
cuz Mexican got on boots."
I said, "Man, how much is a personal
knife going to cost me?" Two bags of
coffee. Come back a little later on
today. I said, "What is the riot jump
off before I get the knife?" He said,
"That ain't my business. That's on you."
I said, "Cool, Cece." So, I wait three
or four hours and I knew he was working
on my knife cuz I was down the cell and
I heard
on the ground. I said, "Yeah, my knife
going to be sharp than a motherfucker."
Cuz I'm hearing it. I'm like I'm hearing
it. I'm like, "Yeah, I can't wait." And
I'm practicing in my cell how I'mma use
my knife.
practicing my
So then this dude named Mitch say, "Hey,
you getting you a knife?" I said, "Yeah,
Cece working on my knife." He said,
"What kind of knife you get?" I said,
"What the is all the knife
questions?"
I said, "I got me a nice little knife."
He say, "It's long. I can hit two, three
people." He said, "Man, you need more
than that." I said, "What I need now?"
He said, "You need to know about how to
fight in a riot." I say how you fighting
the ride. He say Mexican got on boots.
This is the reason why they have on
boots. So they can kick you in this
shin while you fighting. Boots
are made out of metal. The metal, it's a
metal tip boot. So you got to do this.
This is Mitch. This is in my cell
teaching me how to be in a riot. Look,
first of all, when you get out there,
stay close to the wall cuz
going to be trying to stab you. I said
that's pretty much what a riot is. So he
said,
I got that part off the top.
That's why I'm getting a knife. Okay.
So, he say you going to have to do a
rock and lean. I said, "What the is
a rock and lean?" Mexicans going to come
out there, they going to have they
knives. You going to have to have your
shirt off with your knife. And when you
do this, you going to have to rock to
see what foot the Mexican going to kick
you with. I said, "This this is too
much. This is too much. It's like a
choreographed dance. I don't
know what the is he doing. So, I'm
waiting to get my knife. I'm in there
fake rocking trying to see what foot
going to come up. How to do that with
you ain't even the ride yet. I
don't know. But I'm out there
practicing.
I go back to CeCe. I say, "Yo, Cece,
I got to go to the recy. look like
it's f to get live. I need my knife." He
say, "Man,
I just sold your knife."
I said, "Man, what the fuck?" See, see,
you said it was a personal knife for me.
It cost two BAGS OF COFFEE. WHY IT'S NOT
PERSONAL NO MORE? HE SAID, "MAN,
it was personal." Then a dude came in
with three bags of coffee. Then he made
it business.
I said, "So you sold my knife?" He said,
"Yeah, sold your knife." I said, "The
ride about to jump off." Hey man, do
what you can do.
So, moral of the story, how I end up, I
get cut cuz I ain't have
knife and I forgot the rock. I'm out
there rocking with no knife.
I've been PRACTICING FOR TWO HOURS.
ROCK. I'm not getting kicked, but I'm
getting cut.
I got cut down my side from a Mexican
who didn't even have on boots.
Heat.
[Music]
[Applause]